# STEPHANIE PROVENCE

Fair Oaks, CA 916-531-0630 smprovence22@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/smprovence/ GitHub: https://github.com/smprov22/ Portfolio: https://sprovence-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A web developer with a strong affinity for design. Spent over 10 years in the film and television industry and have strong storytelling abilities and excel in making things as user friendly as possible. Strong ability to collaborate and problem solve served me well in the film industry and is also very relevant in web design and development.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Languages/Tools:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Firebase, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars, PHP, WordPress, Drupal, Sequelize, MySQL, Mongo, Mongoose, and React

**Design Software:** Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe inDesign, Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Project Title — Chatbot Concierge

August 2019

Many budget and chain hotels operate without a concierge but hotel patrons still want to know about activities that they can do in the local area. Many activities that give a town or city character are free but there is no good resource to find these activities. We built a website to show local activities tailored to the guest with 5 questions. Our stretch goal is to use this to create an Alexa skill to work with our app/site.

- Tools Used: React, CSS3, JavaScript, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Express.js, Passport.js
- https://chatbot-concierge.herokuapp.com/
- https://github.com/smprov22/Chatbot-Concierge

#### **Project Title** — Rapid Logger

July 2019

The Rapid Logger is designed to be a personal task management system that helps capture and organize tasks/events/thoughts quickly and easily. The brain often doesn't work in an orderly fashion so organizing a task manager that way doesn't always work. The rapid logger allows the user to quickly type in their events/tasks/notes using designated hotkeys and then they are automatically sorted in the task manager.

- Tools Used: HTML5, CSS3, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Node.js, Express,js, Handlebars, Passport.js, Sequelize
- https://rapid-logger.herokuapp.com/
- https://github.com/smprov22/Rapid-Logger

## Project Title — TRVL

May 2019

A one-stop-shop travel website where users can search a variety of destinations with high quality photos, weather information, and a map with information specific to the city. Users can also compare their current search with previous searches.

- Tools Used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, Bootstrap
- https://smprov22.github.io/TRVL./
- https://aithub.com/smprov22/TRVL.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Freelance - Web Developer

Sacramento, CA

August 2019 - present

- Create and design websites for clients on a freelance basis
- Work with clients to figure out exactly what they want from their site and how to achieve it
- Tools used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP

## Freelance - Video Editor

Sacramento, CA

July 2018 - present

- Edit narrative, documentary, corporate, cooking and social media videos for a variety of companies including Warner Brothers, Disney, Insight Editions, Hestan Cue, and more
- Create graphic and text elements to incorporate into videos
- Tools Used: Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop

## **Digital Deployment - Content Migration Analyst**

Sacramento, CA

Sept 2019 - Nov 2020

- Assist the migration team in moving content from old website to a sandbox site using custom CMS
- Format content, create tables, and add links and files to pages
- Proofread all content and correct spelling and grammar errors as needed
- Tools Used: Drupal, HTML, CSS

#### CBS - Writer/Producer

Sacramento, CA

Aug 2019 - April 2020

- Write and produce nightly topicals for the 4pm, 6:30pm, and 10pm news
- Work with creative director to write the most interesting tease possible
- Communicate with news team and anchors to stay up to date on current stories

#### Bix Pix Entertainment - Editor - Tumble Leaf

Sun Valley, CA

February 2016 - March 2018

- Assembled animatics with the director and storyboard team
- Worked closely with visual effects team to implement vfx into each episode
- Part of the team that won 3 Annie Awards and 13 Daytime Emmy Awards
- Tools Used: Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects

#### Thrive Market - Lead Video Editor/Producer

Marina Del Rey, CA

October 2015 - February 2016

- Launched the video channel for Thrive Market
- Edited healthy living, food, and documentary videos
- Maintained the schedule and managed other editors
- Tools Used: Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Certificate - Full Stack Developer

UC Davis Coding Bootcamp - Davis, CA 2019

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, iQuery, AJAX, Firebase, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars, Seguelize, mySQL, Mongo, Mongoose, and React

BA in Cinema Arts California State University Monterey Bay - Seaside, CA 2007

Major in Film Studies with an Emphasis in Editing. Graduated Magna Cum Laude.